Daniel Rosenbaum

Fairfax, VA 22031 | Phone: (703) 615-2053 | Email: Drosenbaum5@gmail.com
GitHub: https://github.com/drosenbaum5 | Portfolio: https://drosenbaum5.github.io/updated-portfolio/
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/daniel-j-rosenbaum/

Professional Summary

Highly motivated and customer service-oriented IT professional growing into a career as a Full Stack Web Developer. Recognized for strong interpersonal communication and effective problem-solving skills. Hands on experience implementing, upgrading, and maintaining various small to medium sized businesses' IT infrastructure to meet customer's needs.

Technical Skills

HTML/CSS + Frameworks (Bootstrap, Materialize, Handlebars), JavaScript + Frameworks (Node.js, React.js, Express.js, Particle.js, Phaser.js), MySQL, MongoDB, Git, Office 365, Unix/Linux, Windows 7/8.1/10, Windows Server 2012 R2/2012

Professional Experience

BoltMSP, System/Network Administrator

2016-2018

- Configure, deploy, upgrade and maintain servers, switches, firewalls, desktops, laptops, iPads, and mobile devices
- Provide Tier 1 and 2 remote/on-site support for 50 small and medium sized businesses. Use TruMethods
 MSP framework to evaluate infrastructure, reduce ticket counts, and resolve issues pro-actively
- Ensure quality education when training new Tier 1 help desk employees
- Build networking labs for training purposes and to ensure software and hardware was compatible before being introduced to production environments
- Modernize and sustain IT infrastructure of healthcare facility with over 350 employees
- Provide on-site support for healthcare facility on weekdays and remote support on evenings and weekends Worked with C level executives, IT Director, and HR Director of healthcare facility to implement
- Workflow policies, employee technical training, IT Policy, and inventory systems

Pazzo Pomodoro, Bartender/ Server

2013-2016

- Accommodated diverse clientele, resolved customer complaints
- Provided top class customer service, as indicated by positive feedback and reviews relationships with regular clientele to gain repeat business and positive working relationship with co-workers and management

Best Buy Assistant Manager, Gaming Department

2010-2011

- Reported to direct manager and store manager regarding sales numbers and marketing
- Maintained high-level product knowledge. Received recognition for conveying product features and benefits, indicated in customer surveys
- Managed all retail duties, including cashier work, restocking, and customer cares

Education

Full Stack Web Development Boot Camp, George Washington University	2019
Associate of Applied Science: Cyber Security, Northern Virginia Community College	2019
CSC: Network Administration, Northern Virginia Community College	2019
CSC: Cyber Security, Northern Virginia Community College	2018

Projects/Portfolio

Choose Your Own Adventure: The Solar System: https://github.com/drosenbaum5/AdventureGame | https://solarsystemadventure.herokuapp.com/

- Choose Your Own Adventure: The Solar System is a retro-style, text-based adventure game with branching story lines designed to educate school-aged children about the solar system.
- Designed all artwork. Worked closely with my team to build front and back ends, and implement full stack functionality using the MERN stack.
- This application was designed using Aseprite, React.js, React Router, React-Bootstrap CSS, React-Sound, Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, JavaScript, Axios, The Solar System OpenData API, Moment.js, and Regex

Destination Podcast: https://github.com/drosenbaum5/destination-podcast | https://drosenbaum5.github.io/destination-podcast/

- Destination Podcast combines the best features of navigation and podcast apps. When a destination is input, the app returns a selection of podcasts based on the length of your trip.
- Designed, planned, and implemented the front end. Worked with a small team on integrating the MapQuest and Listen Notes APIs into the project.
- Technologies used include HTML, CSS, Materialize, JavaScript, jQuery, Listed notes API, MapQuest API, and voice recognition.

First Year: https://github.com/drosenbaum5/HarryPotter | https://harrypotter-csd.herokuapp.com/

- First year is a quiz-based story building game. After inputting your information, a series of quizzes determines a story built around your first year at Hogwarts School of Witchcraft & Wizardry.
- Created wireframe sketches for site. Worked with a small team to develop the front and back ends using a templating engine and database.
- Technologies used to create this project were HTML, CSS, Handlebars, Particle.js, Materialize, Node, Express, and Sequelize.

Human Friend Finder: https://github.com/drosenbaum5/FriendFinder | https://polar-peak-64793.herokuapp.com/survey

- Human Friend Finder is a tongue-in-cheek quiz application designed to help a robot find human friends post apocalypse
- Solo project. Created wireframe for site and Implemented front end and routes.
- This project was created using HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, and Express.